In this series, there is going to be clips involving working the heavy bag.
As part of the introduction, what I want to stress is to actually wear a lot of protection.
You should always wrap your hands first, there's also little slip-wrap covers you can wear if you don't want to do the actual wrapping.
And then, a good pair of bag gloves also.
The other thing I want to stress is: don't think you need to spend ten or fifteen minutes at a time on one bag, just hitting that same bag over and over again.
What I like to see is approximately nine rounds per night on the heavy bag.
But what I like to see is have the boxer do three rounds with a normal speed and power and then go do something else, speed bag or something, and then come back to the heavy bag again.
This time concentrating on power, maybe using a heavier bag.
Don't worry about the speed part - just on power.
And then, go do something else, double-end bag maybe.
Then come back again to the heavy bag, this time concentrate on speed.
Don't worry about your power, don't worry about getting everything perfect, just snap off a lot of punches.
Maybe wear the punch mitts and actually get a good count on a number of punches.
So, a little bit later, we're going to be discussing all the different moves on a heavy bag, and exactly what we need to do.